<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<document size="LETTER" margin-left="25" margin-right="25" margin-top="25" margin-bottom="25" rotate="true">
<encryption allow-fillin="false" allow-modify-contents="false" allow-degraded-printing="true" allow-screen-readers="false" allow-copy="false"	allow-printing="false"/>
<meta author="JIMS2, Harris County" creator="JIMS2, Harris County" title="Restricted Access (English)"/>

	<module>
		<color-def name="custom-brown" color-space="RGB" value="153,0,51"/>
	
		<font-def name="Kristen-ITC" family="Kristen-ITC" style="bold" size="10" color="custom-brown"/>
		<font-def name="Kristen-ITC-18" family="Kristen-ITC" style="bold" size="18" color="custom-brown"/>
		<font-def name="Kristen-ITC-13" family="Kristen-ITC" style="bold" size="13" color="custom-brown"/>
		
		<font-def name="Goudy-Old-Style-12" family="Goudy-Old-Style" style="bold" size="12" color="custom-brown"/>
		<font-def name="Goudy-Old-Style-12b" family="Goudy-Old-Style" style="normal" size="12" color="black"/>
		<font-def name="Goudy-Old-Style-11" family="Goudy-Old-Style" style="normal" size="11" color="custom-brown"/>
		<font-def name="Arial-Rounded-MT-Bold-9w" family="Arial-Rounded-MT-Bold" style="normal" size="9" color="white"/>
		
		<font-def name="arial-9" family="arial" style="normal" size="9"/>
		<font-def name="arial-10" family="arial" style="normal" size="10"/>
		<font-def name="arial-12" family="arial" style="normal" size="12"/>
		<font-def name="arial-7" family="arial" style="normal" size="7"/>
		
		<font-def name="Eras-Medium-ITC-10" family="Eras-Medium-ITC" style="normal" size="10"/>
		<font-def name="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" family="Eras-Medium-ITC" style="bold" size="12"/>
		<font-def name="Eras-Medium-ITC-18" family="Eras-Medium-ITC" style="bold" size="18"/>
		<font-def name="Eras-Medium-ITC-18b" family="Eras-Medium-ITC" style="bold" size="18" color="custom-brown"/>
		<font-def name="Eras-Medium-ITC-14" family="Eras-Medium-ITC" style="bold" size="14"/>
		<font-def name="Symbol-10" family="Symbol" style="bold" size="10" color="custom-brown"/>
	</module>
	
	
	<table columns="3" widths="33,33,33" padding="10" border-style="none">
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="5">
				How does the &quot;Restricted Access&quot; records system benefit my child?
			</paragraph>
			<table columns="2" widths="5,95" border-style="none" padding="0" spacing-after="5">
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell fill-row="true">if a juvenile&apos;s records are placed on restricted access, the juvenile may:</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>deny the existence of the juvenile record and</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>deny the arrest, prosecution or adjudication ever happened.</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
			<paragraph spacing-after="5" font="arial-9">
				For example, once your juvenile records are on restricted access, you may legally answer, 
				&quot;<i>No</i>&quot; when a job application, educational or occupational licensing application asks, 
				&quot;Have you ever been arrested, convicted or adjudicated of a crime?&quot;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph spacing-after="5" font="arial-9">
				It is important to understand that if you commit a crime after turning age 17 and you are 
				convicted of or placed on deferred adjudication for the offense in adult criminal court, your 
				records are not eligible for Restricted Access.  You do not have the right to deny the existence 
				of your juvenile record.  If you deny in this situation, you could be prosecuted for perjury 
				(failing to tell the truth).
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph spacing-after="10" font="arial-9">
				If you commit a crime after turning 21, your records will be removed from restricted access.  
				You would then also lose your right to deny the existence of your juvenile record.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				What should I do to make sure my records are placed on &quot;Restricted Access?&quot;
			</paragraph>
			<table columns="2" widths="5,95" border-style="none" padding="0" spacing-after="10">
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell fill-row="true">To be sure your records are eligible for and placed on restricted access you must:</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>successfully complete your period of probation or parole with no violations; and</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>commit no criminal offense after becoming 17 years of age</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
			
			<paragraph spacing-after="10" font="arial-9">
				The Restricted Access system truly gives juveniles the opportunity for rehabilitation and 
				a fresh start if they do not commit any further criminal offenses.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				When does this new system take effect?
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph spacing-after="10" font="arial-9">
				The new law goes into effect September 1, 2001. It applies to all juvenile records created before, 
				on or after September 1, 2001.  
			</paragraph>

		</cell>
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				Should I still try to get my records sealed or destroyed?
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph spacing-after="20" font="arial-9" >
				The sealing and destruction of juvenile records procedures do offer some additional benefits to 
				a juvenile and may be the preferred course of action.  To have your record sealed, you must initiate 
				a formal court proceeding and may need an attorney.  Also, if you have criminal records in a justice 
				or municipal court, special expungement procedures apply.  If you have questions about any of these 
				procedures, discuss them with your attorney or your probation or parole officer.
			</paragraph>
			
			<table columns="1" width="80" border-style="top" border-width="4" border-color="custom-brown" halign="center" padding="0">
				<table-row font="Goudy-Old-Style-12" halign="center" padding-bottom="5" padding-top="5">
					<cell>Prepared by the</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="Goudy-Old-Style-12" halign="center" border-style="none">
					<cell>Texas Juvenile Probation Commission</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="Goudy-Old-Style-11" halign="center" border-style="none" padding-bottom="10">
					<cell>
						4900 N. Lamar Boulevard<br/>
						P.O. Box 13547, Austin, Texas 78711<br/>
						Phone (512) 424-6700<br/>
						TDD (512) 424-4000<br/>
						www.tjpc.state.tx.us<br/>
					</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="Goudy-Old-Style-12" halign="center" border-style="none">
					<cell>Texas Youth Commission</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="Goudy-Old-Style-11" halign="center" border-style="none" padding-bottom="20">
					<cell>
						4900 N. Lamar Boulevard<br/>
						P.O. Box 4260, Austin, Texas 78765<br/>
						Phone (512) 424-6130<br/>
						TDD (512) 424-4000<br/>
						www.tyc.state.tx.us<br/>
					</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
			
			<table columns="1" width="100" bgcolor="custom-brown" border-style="box" border-width="5" border-color="custom-brown">
				<table-row padding-bottom="10" padding-top="10">
					<cell font="Arial-Rounded-MT-Bold-9w" align="center">
						For additional copies or if you have questions, please contact your local juvenile probation or parole office at:
					</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row bgcolor="white" halign="center" font="arial-9" padding-bottom="10" padding-top="10">
					<cell>
						<b>${probationOfficer.fullNameFirst}</b><br/>
						${locationUnitName}<br/>
						${locationUnitAddress}<br/>
						${officerPhone}<br/>
					</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row bgcolor="white" font="arial-7" halign="right" padding-bottom="10" padding-top="10" border-style="none">
					<cell valign="top">ADM-058</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
		</cell>
		<cell halign="center" valign="top">
			<image source="MJCW/RA_Topline.jpg" width="220" scale-to-fit="true"/><br/><br/>
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC-18" spacing-after="20" halign="center">
				Texas<br/>
				Juvenile Justice System Files and Records
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC-13" halign="center">
				A Parent and Child&apos;s Guide to Understanding<br/>
				Automatic Restriction of Access to Records
			</paragraph>
			
			<image source="MJCW/RA_Filing_Cabinet.jpg" width="140" scale-to-fit="true"/>
			<paragraph spacing-after="20" font="Goudy-Old-Style-12b" halign="center">
				A Publication By The<br/>
				<i>Texas Juvenile Probation Commission and the Texas Youth Commission</i><br/>
				March 2003

			</paragraph>
			<image source="MJCW/RA_Bottomline.jpg" width="220" scale-to-fit="true"/>
		</cell>
	</table>

	<new-page size="LETTER" margin-left="25" margin-right="25" margin-top="25" margin-bottom="25" rotate="true"/>

	<table columns="3" widths="33,33,33" padding="10" border-style="none">
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<image x="170" y="490" source="MJCW/RA_Policeman.jpg" width="100" scale-to-fit="true"/>
			<table columns="1" width="100" border-style="none" spacing-after="20" padding="0">
				<table-row font="Kristen-ITC" padding-bottom="10">
					<cell>
						Who has a &quot;Juvenile File<br/>
						and Record&quot; in Texas?
					</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row>				
					<cell font="arial-9">
						If you have been arrested,<br/> 
						taken into custody or charged<br/>
						with a criminal offense (Class<br/>
						A or B misdemeanor or any <br/>
						felony) that was committed when <br/>
						you were at least 10 years old but younger than 17 years old, you probably have a juvenile file and record.  
						You may also have a juvenile record if you were charged with some Class C misdemeanor offenses 
						if the justice or municipal court transferred your case to a juvenile court.
					</cell>
				</table-row>	
			</table>
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				What are &quot;Juvenile Justice Files and Records&quot;?
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-9" spacing-after="20">
				Under the record keeping system for juvenile records in Texas, if a juvenile was 
				adjudicated for delinquent conduct (Class A or B misdemeanor or any felony), 
				the juvenile probably has a juvenile record with numerous entities including local law enforcement, 
				the Texas Department of Public Safety (DPS) and the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI).  
				That record is a permanent record that is not destroyed or erased unless the record is eligible 
				for sealing and the child or the child's family hires a lawyer to file a petition in court to have 
				the record sealed.  
			</paragraph>
			<image x="40" y="170" source="MJCW/RA_Folder.jpg" width="80" scale-to-fit="true" textwrap="true" underlying="false"/>
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				Who usually has access to Juvenile Records?
			</paragraph>
			<table columns="2" widths="37,63" spacing-after="10" padding="0">
				<table-row>
					<cell></cell>
					<cell font="arial-9">
						While juvenile files and records are generally confidential, there are some important exceptions.  
						A juvenile record can be accessed by police, sheriff's officers, prosecutors, probation officers, 
						
					</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row>
					<cell font="arial-9" fill-row="true">
						correctional officers, and other criminal and juvenile justice officials in this state and elsewhere.  
						Also, the record may be available to employers, educational institutions, licensing agencies, and other 
						organizations when the person applies for employment or educational programs.  Juvenile treatment records 
						(counseling, placement, drug treatment, etc.) are confidential and accessible only to authorized users.
					</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
			
		</cell>
		
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				What is the &quot;Automatic Restriction of Access to Records System&quot;?
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-9" spacing-after="20">
				In Texas there now exists a records system that is designed to limit access to your juvenile records 
				after you reach 21 years of age <b><u>if</u></b> you do not commit criminal offenses after becoming 17 years of age.  
				The system is called &quot;<b><i>Automatic Restriction of Access to Records.</i></b>&quot; This is in addition to your opportunity 
				to have your records sealed and destroyed under other provisions of the Texas Family Code.  
			</paragraph>	
			<paragraph font="arial-9" spacing-after="20">
				Under automatic restriction of access to records, your records are not destroyed or sealed.  
				They remain in place, but under restricted access.  They are available only to criminal justice 
				agencies for criminal justice purposes, such as investigating and prosecuting crimes. 
				For all other inquiries--employment, education, etc.--the holder of the records is required to reply 
				that the records &quot;do not exist&quot; and you are legally allowed to deny that you were ever arrested, prosecuted 
				or adjudicated for a crime.
			</paragraph>
			
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				How do a Juvenile&apos;s Records become eligible for &quot;Restricted Access&quot;?
			</paragraph>			
			<table columns="2" widths="5,95" border-style="none" padding="0" spacing-after="20">
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell fill-row="true">For restricted access to take place, no action is required by the child or the child&apos;s family.  
						You do not have to file a petition or hire a lawyer.  The process occurs automatically at age 21 if, 
						since your 17th birthday, you have <u>not</u></cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>committed a felony or a Class A or B misdemeanor; or</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>received deferred adjudication for or been convicted in adult court of a Class A or B misdemeanor or a felony.</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
				
			<paragraph font="arial-9" spacing-after="20">
				If you meet the requirements set out above you will be given a fresh start when you reach age 21.  
				This allows you to pursue various employment and educational opportunities without your past record in the juvenile system to harm you.  
				But remember, this opportunity will only happen if you do not commit any criminal offenses.  
				If you commit a crime after turning 21, your records will be removed from restricted access.
			</paragraph>
		</cell>
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				What does it mean if records are placed on &quot;Restricted Access&quot;?
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-9" spacing-after="20">
				If a juvenile&apos;s record is placed on restricted access when the respondent becomes 21 years of age, 
				access to the record will be denied to employers, educational institutions, and other persons who 
				may want the information.  Only criminal justice agencies will have access to these records and only 
				for a criminal justice purpose, which includes investigation of crimes and for the screening of persons 
				who apply for employment in a criminal justice agency (police officers, etc).
			</paragraph>
			
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				What records are not eligible for &quot;Restricted Access&quot;?
			</paragraph>
			<table columns="2" widths="5,95" border-style="none" padding="0" spacing-after="20">
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell fill-row="true">The only juvenile records that are not eligible for automatic restricted access are cases that were:</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>handled as determinate sentence cases by the juvenile court;</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>certified (transferred) to adult criminal court to be handled in the same manner as adult cases; or</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row font="arial-9">
					<cell font="Symbol-10">&#183;</cell>
					<cell>prosecuted in justice or municipal court.</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
			
			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				What about Gang Records?
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-9" spacing-after="20">
				Information about gang activity is maintained by DPS in gang book records as authorized by law.  
				These records are exempt from the new system because the access to these records is already limited 
				to criminal justice agencies for a criminal justice purpose.
			</paragraph>

			<paragraph font="Kristen-ITC" spacing-after="10">
				What about Sex Offender Records?
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-9" spacing-after="20">
				Sex offender registration records are exempted from the Restricted Access system because 
				the purpose of registration is to notify the public.  If you are a registered juvenile sex offender, 
				you may have a right to have your records sealed once your obligation to register expires. 
				Also, there are other legal proceedings that may allow reconsideration of your obligation to register.  
				Talk to your probation or parole officer about these, or speak to a private attorney. 
			</paragraph>
		</cell>
	</table>
	
	<new-page size="LEGAL" margin-left="25" margin-right="25" margin-top="25" margin-bottom="25" rotate="true"/>
	
	<table columns="4" widths="25,25,25,25" padding="5" border-style="none">
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.208 INFORMATION TO CHILD ON DISCHARGE
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				On the final discharge of a child from the juvenile system or on the last official action in the case, 
				if there is no adjudication, the appropriate juvenile justice official shall provide to the child:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) a written explanation of how automatic restricted access under this subchapter works;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) a copy of this subchapter; and
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(3) a statement that if the child wishes to receive notification of an action restricting access to the child&apos;s records under 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				Section 58.207(a), the child must before the child&apos;s
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				21st birthday provide the juvenile probation department with a current address where the child can receive notification
			</paragraph>
			
			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.209. INFORMATION TO CHILD BY PROBATION OFFICER OR TEXAS YOUTH COMMISSION 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(a) When a child is placed on probation for an offense that may be eligible for automatic restricted access at 
				age 21 or when a child is received by the Texas Youth Commission on an indeterminate commitment, 
				a probation officer or an official at the Texas Youth Commission reception center, as soon as practicable, 
				shall explain the substance of the following information to the child: 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) if the child was adjudicated as having committed delinquent conduct for a felony or jailable misdemeanor, that the child 
				probably has a juvenile record with the department and the Federal Bureau of Investigation. 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) that the child&apos;s juvenile record is a permanent record that is not destroyed or erased unless the record 
				is eligible for sealing and the child or the child&apos;s family hires a lawyer and files a petition in court to have 
				the record sealed.
			</paragraph>
		</cell>
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(3) that the child&apos;s juvenile record, other than treatment records made confidential by law, can be accessed by
				police, sheriff&apos;s officers, prosecutors, probation officers, correctional officers, and other criminal and 
				juvenile justice officials in this state and elsewhere.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(4) that the child&apos;s juvenile record, other than treatment records made confidential by law, can be accessed by employers, 
				educational institutions, licensing agencies, and other organizations when the child applies for employment or educational 
				programs: 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(5) if the child&apos;s juvenile record is placed on restricted access when the child becomes 21 years of age, 
				that access will be denied to employers, educational institutions, and others except for criminal justice agencies:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(6) that to have the child&apos;s juvenile record placed on restricted access at age 21, the child must not: 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(A) commit a felony or jailable misdemeanor; and 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(B) receive deferred adjudication for or be convicted in adult court of a felony or jailable misdemeanor; and 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(7) that restricted access does not require any action by the child or the child&apos;s family, 
				including the filing of a petition or hiring a lawyer, but occurs automatically at age 21 if 
				the child does not commit a criminal offense in the future. 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(b) The probation officer of Texas Youth Commission official shall: 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) give the child a written copy of the explanation provided; and 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) communicate the same information to at least one of the child&apos;s parents or, if none can be found, 
				to the child&apos;s guardian or custodian.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(c) The Texas Juvenile Probation Commission and the Texas Youth Commission shall adopt rules to 
				implement this section and to facilitate the effective explanation of the information required to be 
				communicated by this section.
			</paragraph>
		</cell>
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			
			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.210. SEALING OR DESTRUCTION OF RECORDS NOT AFFECTED
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(a)  This subchapter does not prevent or restrict the sealing or destruction of juvenile records a authorized by law.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(b) Restricted access provided under this subchapter is in addition to sealing or destruction of juvenile records.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(c)  A person who is the subject of records certified under this subchapter is entitled to access to the records 
				for the purpose of preparing and presenting a motion to seal or destroy the records.
			</paragraph>

			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.211 RESCINDING RESTRICTED ACCESS
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(a) If the department has notified a juvenile probation department that a record has been placed on restricted access 
				and the department later receives information in the department&apos;s criminal history system that the subject of the record 
				has been convicted of or placed on deferred adjudication for a felony or a misdemeanor punishable by confinement in jail 
				for an offense committed after the person reached the age of 17, the person&apos;s juvenile records are no longer subject to 
				restricted access.  The department shall notify the appropriate local juvenile probation departments in the manner 
				described by Section 58.203 that the person&apos;s records are no longer subject to restricted access.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10">
				(b) On receipt of the notification described by Subsection (a), the juvenile probation department shall notify the 
				agencies  that maintain the person&apos;s juvenile records under Section 58.207(b) that the person&apos;s records are no longer 
				subject to restricted access. 
			</paragraph>
			<br/><br/><br/><br/><br/>
			<font name="Eras-Medium-ITC-10">Rev. 9/2005</font>
		</cell>
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<table columns="1" width="80" border-style="top|bottom" border-width="4" border-color="custom-brown" halign="center" spacing-after="20">
				<table-row>
					<cell font="Eras-Medium-ITC-18b" padding-bottom="10">
						<i>Harris County Juvenile Probation Department</i>
					</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row>
					<cell font="Eras-Medium-ITC-18b" border-style="none" padding-bottom="20">
						<i>Statutes Relating To Access, Sealing and Destruction of Juvenile Records</i>
					</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
			
			<table columns="1" width="80" border-style="box" border-width="4" border-color="custom-brown" 
				halign="center" spacing-after="20" padding-top="20" padding-bottom="20">
				<table-row>
					<cell font="Eras-Medium-ITC-14">
						The Information contained in this brochure is provided to youth on probation and their parents or guardian 
						as required by the Texas Family Code, Section 58.
					</cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
			
			<table columns="1" width="80" border-style="none" halign="center">
				<table-row>
					<cell><image source="MJCW/RA_Topline.jpg" width="150" scale-to-fit="true" halign="center"/></cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row>
					<cell font="Eras-Medium-ITC-14">
						1200 Congress<br/>
						Houston Texas 77002<br/>
						 Telephone: 713.222.4100<br/>
						September 2005
					</cell>
				</table-row>
				<table-row>
					<cell><image source="MJCW/RA_Bottomline.jpg" width="150" scale-to-fit="true" halign="center"/></cell>
				</table-row>
			</table>
		</cell>
	</table>
	
	<new-page size="LEGAL" margin-left="25" margin-right="25" margin-top="25" margin-bottom="25" rotate="true"/>
	
	<table columns="4" widths="25,25,25,25" padding="5" border-style="none">
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="arial-12" spacing-after="5">
				<b>58.201. DEFINITION</b>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				In this subchapter, &quot;department&quot; means the Department of Public Safety of the State of Texas.
			</paragraph>
			
			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.202. EXEMPTED RECORDS
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				The following records are exempt from this subchapter.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) sex offender registration records maintained by the department or a local law enforcement 
				agency under  Chapter 62, Code of Criminal Procedure; and
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) records relating to a criminal combination or criminal street gang maintained by the 
				department or a local law enforcement agency Chapter 61, Code of Criminal Procedure.
			</paragraph>

			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.203. CERTIFICATION 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(a) The department shall certify to the juvenile probation department to which a referral 
				was made that resulted in information being submitted to the juvenile justice information 
				system that the records relating to a person&apos;s juvenile case are  subject to automatic 
				restriction of access if:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) the person is at least 21 years of age;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) the juvenile case did not include violent or habitual felony conduct resulting in 
				proceedings in the juvenile court under Section 53.045; 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(3) the juvenile case was not certified for trial in criminal court under Section 54.02; and
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(4) the department has not received a report in its criminal history system that the 
				person was granted deferred adjudication  for or convicted of a felony or a
				misdemeanor punishable by confinement in  a jail for an offense committed after the 
				person became 17 years of age.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(b) If the department&apos;s records relate to a juvenile court with multicounty jurisdiction, 
				the department shall issue the certification described by Subsection (a) to each juvenile 
				probation department shall determine
			</paragraph>
 
		</cell>
		
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				whether it received the referral and, if it received the referral, take the restrictive 
				action notification required by law. 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(c) The department may issue the certification described by Subsection (a) by electronic means, 
				including by electronic mail. 
			</paragraph>
			
			<paragraph spacing-after="20">
				<font name="Eras-Medium-ITC-12">58.204 RESTRICTED ACCESS ON CERTIFICATION</font>
				<font name="arial-10">(a) On certification of records in a case under Section 58.203, the department, except as provided by Subsection (b):</font>
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1)  may not disclose the existence of the records or any information from the records in response to an inquiry from:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(A) a law enforcement agency;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(B) a criminal or juvenile justice agency;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(C) a governmental or other agency given access to information under Chapter 411, Government Code; or
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(D) any other person, agency, organization, or entity; and
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) shall respond to a request for information about the records by stating that the records do not exist.
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(b) On certification of records in a case under Section 58.203, the department may permit access to the 
				information in the juvenile justice information system relating to the case of an individual only: 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) by a criminal justice agency for a criminal justice purpose, as those terms are defined by 
				Section 411.082, Government Code; or 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) for research purposes, by the Texas Juvenile Probation Commission, the Texas Youth Commission or 
				the Criminal Justice Policy Council.
			</paragraph>
		</cell>
		
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.205. REQUEST TO THE FEDERAL BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION ON CERTIFICATION
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				On certification of records in a case under Section 58.203, the department shall request the Federal Bureau of Investigation to:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) place the information in its files on restricted status, with access only by a criminal justice agency for 
				a criminal justice purpose, as those terms are defined by Section 411.082, Government Code; or  
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) if the action described in Subdivision (1) is not feasible, delete all information in its database concerning the case.
			</paragraph>

			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.206. EFFECT OF CERTIFICATION IN RELATION TO THE PROTECTED PERSON
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(a) On certification of records in a case under Section 58.203:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) the person who is the subject of the records is not required to state in any proceeding, 
				except as otherwise authorized by law in a criminal proceeding in which the person is testifying 
				as a defendant, or in any application for employment, licensing, or other public or private benefit 
				that the person has been a respondent in a case under this title and may not be punished, 
				by perjury prosecution or otherwise, for denying:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(A) the existence of the records; or 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(B) the person&apos;s participation in a juvenile proceeding related to the records; and
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) information from the records may not be admitted against the person who is the subject of the records 
				in a civil or criminal proceeding except a proceeding in which a juvenile adjudication was admitted under:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(A) Section 12.42, Penal Code;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(B) Article 37.07, Code of Criminal Procedure; or 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(C) as otherwise authorized by criminal procedural law.
			</paragraph>

		</cell>
		
		<cell halign="left" valign="top">
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(b) A person who is the subject of records certified under this subchapter may not waive the restricted 
				status of the records or the consequences of the restricted status.
			</paragraph>
			
			<paragraph font="Eras-Medium-ITC-12" spacing-after="5">
				58.207. JUVENILE COURT ORDERS ON CERTIFICATION
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(a) On certification of records in a case under Section 58.203, the juvenile court shall order: 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) that the following records relating to the case may be accessed only as provided by Section 58.204(b):
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(A) if the respondent was committed to the Texas Youth Commission, records maintained by the commission;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(B) records maintained by the juvenile probation department;
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(C) records maintained by the clerk of the court:    
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(D) records maintained by the prosecutor&apos;s office; and 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(E) records maintained by the law enforcement agency; and
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) the juvenile probation department to make a reasonable effort to notify the person who is the 
				subject of records for which access has been restricted of the action restricting access and the legal 
				significance of the action for the person, but only if the person has requested the notification 
				in writing and has provided the juvenile probation department with a current address. 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(b) On receipt of an order under Subsection (a) (1), the agency maintaining the records:
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(1) may allow access only as provided by Section 58.204(b): and 
			</paragraph>
			<paragraph font="arial-10" spacing-after="5">
				(2) shall respond to a request for information about the records by stating that the record exists   
			</paragraph>
		</cell>
	</table>
	
    
</document>