<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<document size="LETTER" margin-left="25" margin-right="25" margin-top="20" margin-bottom="20">
<encryption allow-fillin="false" allow-modify-contents="false" allow-degraded-printing="true" allow-screen-readers="false" allow-copy="false"	allow-printing="false"/>
<meta author="JIMS2, Harris County" creator="JIMS2, Harris County" title="Hire Attorney Report"/>

<module>
	<font-def name="text" family="Helvetica" style="normal" size="10"/>
	<font-def name="title" family="Helvetica" style="bold" size="11"/>
	<font-def name="header" family="Helvetica" style="bold|underline" size="11"/>
    
	<custom-tag alias="std-paragraph" tag="paragraph">
		<attribute name="font" value="text"/>
		<attribute name="spacing-after" value="5"/>
	</custom-tag>
	
	<custom-tag alias="std-title" tag="paragraph">
		<attribute name="font" value="title"/>
		<attribute name="spacing-after" value="8"/>
	</custom-tag>
	
	<custom-tag alias="std-header" tag="paragraph">
		<attribute name="font" value="header"/>
		<attribute name="spacing-after" value="8"/>
	</custom-tag>
	
	<custom-tag alias="shr-label" tag="phrase">
			<attribute name="font" value="label"/>
		</custom-tag>
		
	<custom-tag alias="shr-text" tag="paragraph">
		<attribute name="font" value="text"/>
	</custom-tag>
	
	<custom-tag alias="shr-tableheader" tag="phrase">
		<attribute name="font" value="tableheader"/>
	</custom-tag>
</module>
        
		<font-def name="label" family="Helvetica" style="bold" size="11"/>
		<font-def name="text-large" family="Helvetica" style="normal" size="12"/>
		<font-def name="tableheader" family="Helvetica" style="bold|underline" size="10"/>
		<font-def name="Symbol-10" family="Symbol" style="bold" size="10" />
		
		<footer padding-top="10">
			<font size="10" color="black">
				<footer-part padding-top="5" halign="left" width="500">
					<table columns="2" width="100" halign="center">
						<table-row halign="left">
							<cell halign="left">
								
								Parental Written Statement - Page ${pageNumber,  nointrprt} of ${pageCount,  nointrprt}
							
							</cell>
							<cell halign="right">
								TJPC-AGE-10-04
							</cell>
						</table-row>
						<table-row halign="left"><cell><br/></cell>
						</table-row>
					</table>
				</footer-part>
			</font>
		</footer>
	

	
    <!--  =============================================================================================================
        Page 1 - Cover Sheet
    -->

	<table columns="1" border-style="none" border-width="0" widths="1" padding="2">
        <cell halign="center" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            <paragraph>
                <image source="MJCW/TexasJuvenileProbationCommisionSeal.jpg" width="75" height="75" scale-to-fit="true"/>
            </paragraph>
        </cell>
	</table>
    
	<std-title halign="center">
		Texas Juvenile Justice Department<br/>
        <font size="12">INSTRUCTIONS FOR PROBATION DEPARTMENTS REGARDING<br/>
        PARENTAL WRITTEN STATEMENTS</font>
	</std-title>
    <br/>
    
	<std-paragraph>
        Effective September 1, 2003, Section 61.104 of the Texas Family Code requires that a 
        parent be given the opportunity to submit a written statement to the juvenile court 
        judge concerning the disposition of their child&apos;s case.  The statute reads as follows:     
	</std-paragraph>

    <br/>
	<std-paragraph>
        <b>&#167; 61.104.  PARENTAL WRITTEN STATEMENT</b>
	</std-paragraph>
    
	<table columns="2" border-style="none" border-width="0" widths="1,10" padding="2">
        <table-row>
            <cell halign="center" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-paragraph>
                    (a)
            	</std-paragraph>
            </cell>
            <cell halign="left" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-paragraph>
                    When a petition for adjudication, a motion or petition to modify disposition, or a 
                    motion or petition for discretionary transfer to criminal court is served on a parent 
                    of the child, the parent must be provided with a form prescribed by the Texas Juvenile 
                    Justice Department on which the parent can make a written statement about the needs of 
                    the child or family or any other matter relevant to disposition of the case.
            	</std-paragraph>
            </cell>
        </table-row>
        <table-row>
            <cell halign="center" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-paragraph>
                    (b)
            	</std-paragraph>
            </cell>
            <cell halign="left" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-paragraph>
                    The parent shall return the statement to the juvenile probation department, which 
                    shall transmit the statement to the court along with the discretionary transfer report 
                    authorized by Section 54.02(e), the disposition report authorized by Section 54.04(b), 
                    or the modification of disposition report authorized by Section 54.05(e), as applicable.  
                    The statement shall be disclosed to the parties as appropriate and may be considered by 
                    the court at the disposition, modification, or discretionary transfer hearing.    
            	</std-paragraph>
            </cell>
        </table-row>
	</table>
    <br/>

    
	<std-paragraph>
        A parental written statement form shall be given to every parent who is summoned in a 
        juvenile case and any other person the juvenile court feels should be given an opportunity 
        to provide a parental written statement to the court.  This may include the child&apos;s guardian, 
        custodian, guardian ad-litem or any other person the court determines is a necessary party 
        to the juvenile&apos;s case. 	
    </std-paragraph>
    
	<std-paragraph>
        Upon request by a parent, the parent must be provided with the Spanish version of the parental 
        written statement form.  The Spanish version of the form is available from the Texas Juvenile 
        Justice Department and may be obtained and downloaded from the Department&apos;s website 
        at: <u>www.tjjd.texas.gov.</u>
    </std-paragraph>
    
	<std-paragraph>
        The juvenile board, juvenile court, prosecutor&apos;s office and/or the juvenile probation department 
        should jointly develop local policies and procedures that address the following steps related 
        to the parental written statement.
	</std-paragraph>

    <list numbered="false" lettered="false" symbol-indent="15">
        <list-symbol>&#183;</list-symbol>
        <list-item spacing-after="10">Provision of the parental written statement form to a parent or other 
            person.  Local policy should address who in the probation department provides the form, 
            when the form is provided and how (i.e., mail, with the summons, etc.).</list-item>
        <list-item spacing-after="10">Completion of the heading of the parental written statement containing 
            the cause number and other case identifying information.  Local policy should address 
            who is responsible for completing the form&apos;s header information, if used.</list-item>
        <list-item spacing-after="10">Provision of instructions for completion of the parental written 
            statement, deadline for the return of the completed statement and delivery of the completed 
            parental written statement to the proper juvenile probation department official.  
            Local policy should address who will provide assistance and instructions to parents 
            regarding the use of the form.</list-item>
        <list-item spacing-after="10">Provision of copies of the completed parental written statement to 
            the prosecutor, defense attorney and any other parties as determined appropriate by the juvenile 
            court. Local policy should address who is responsible for ensuring all appropriate parties 
            receive a copy of the completed statement in a timely manner.</list-item>
        <list-item spacing-after="10">Submittal of the completed parental written statement to the juvenile 
            court judge along with any social history or other dispositional report.  Local policy should 
            address who is responsible for providing the court a copy of the completed statement.</list-item>
    </list>

    
    <!--  =============================================================================================================
        Page 2  
    -->
    
	<new-page size="LETTER" margin-left="10" margin-right="10" margin-top="10" margin-bottom="10">
	</new-page>

	<table columns="2" border-style="none" border-width="0" widths="4,2" padding="1" keep-together="true">
    
        <!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
            Left side of page 2.  
        -->
        
        <cell halign="left" valign="top" leading="1" padding="8" line-spacing="1">

            <std-title halign="center">
                <font size="12">Instructions for Making a Parental Written Statement</font>
        	</std-title>
    
            <std-header halign="center">
                PARA RECIBIR ESTAS INSTRUCCIONES Y LA FORMA<br/>
                EN ESPANOL PONGASE EN CONTACTO CON<br/>
                EL DEPARTAMENTO JUVENIL NOMBRADO ABAJO 
        	</std-header>
            <br/>
        
            <std-paragraph>
                Texas Family Code Section 61.104 requires that the parent of a child who is accused of 
                breaking the law and who will appear before a Texas juvenile court must be given the 
                opportunity to give a parental written statement to the court.     
        	</std-paragraph>

            <std-paragraph>
                A parental written statement is your opportunity to tell the court information about 
                your child&apos;s and family&apos;s needs, strengths or other important information related to 
                your child&apos;s case.   The judge may consider this statement when making a final decision 
                in your child&apos;s case.  
        	</std-paragraph>

            <std-paragraph>
                A parental written statement may be submitted when any of the following legal documents 
                have been filed in the juvenile court regarding your child:
        	</std-paragraph>

            <list numbered="false" lettered="false" symbol-indent="15">
                <list-symbol>-</list-symbol>
                <list-item>A petition for an adjudication hearing;</list-item>
                <list-item>A motion or petition for a modification hearing to change your child&apos;s 
                    probation conditions; or </list-item>
                <list-item>A motion or petition for a discretionary transfer hearing for possible 
                    transfer of your child to a criminal court where he or she will be tried as an adult.</list-item>
            </list>

            <std-paragraph>
                Any information you provide will NOT be used in the adjudication hearing which is a 
                hearing to determine whether or not your child committed the offense.  It may be used 
                in the disposition hearing which may assist the court in making a final disposition 
                decision about your child&apos;s case that may include the following actions:    
        	</std-paragraph>

           	<list numbered="false" lettered="false" symbol-indent="15">
                <list-symbol>-</list-symbol>
                <list-item>Placing your child on probation in your home;</list-item>
                <list-item>Placing your child on probation outside your home with relatives or other persons;</list-item>
                <list-item>Placing your child on probation in a secure facility or non-secure residential 
                    facility for juveniles; or </list-item>
                <list-item>Commitment of your child to the Texas Juvenile Justice Department.</list-item>
            </list>

            <std-paragraph>
                If both parents reside together in the home with your child, only one parental written 
                statement per family may be submitted.  If you are divorced or separated, then both 
                parents will be allowed to submit their own separate statements.  
        	</std-paragraph>

            <std-paragraph>
                <u>A parental written statement is completely voluntary and you may choose not to make 
                a statement in connection with your child&apos;s case.</u> You may choose to respond 
                to any or all of the sections on this form.  Although examples are provided, you are not 
                limited to those examples.  Your entire statement will be shared with the judge, the juvenile 
                probation department, your child&apos;s defense attorney, the prosecutor and any other person 
                the juvenile court determines should be provided with a copy.  Any information you submit 
                to the court may be used against your child; therefore, you may want to consult with an 
                attorney about the consequences of providing a statement to the juvenile court.  If you 
                choose to provide a statement, you may submit it on your own paper and use any form you 
                choose.  You may also attach sheets of paper to this form if you need additional space.  
                When your statement is completed, please return it to the juvenile probation department 
                at the address below.  If you return your statement to the juvenile probation department, 
                the juvenile probation department will provide your statement to the juvenile court.      
        	</std-paragraph>

            <std-paragraph>
                For any questions regarding the completion of the written parental statement you may 
                contact the juvenile probation department listed below.  Upon completion of the written 
                parental statement, please mail or hand-deliver this form on or before the deadline on 
                the front page of the form to:
        	</std-paragraph>

            <std-paragraph halign="center" spacing-after="20">
                ${locationUnitName}<br/>
                ${locationAddress.streetNum} ${locationAddress.streetName} ${locationAddress.streetTypeCode} ${locationAddress.aptNum}<br/>
                ${locationAddress.city}
				_if_(${locationAddress.city} isDefined), _endif_
				${locationAddress.stateCode} ${locationAddress.zipCode}<br/>
                ${locationUnitPhone.formattedPhoneNumber}
        	</std-paragraph>
            
            <std-paragraph>
                <i>If you need an additional copy of these instructions or written parental statement, 
                you may request it from the juvenile probation department.  This form is also available 
                from the Texas Juvenile Justice Department on the Internet and may be downloaded at 
                <u>www.tjjd.texas.gov.</u></i>
        	</std-paragraph>
    
        </cell>
        
        <!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
            Right side of page 2.  
        -->
        
        <cell valign="top" halign="left" leading="1" padding="8" line-spacing="1" border-style="box" border-width="2">
        
            <br/>
            <std-title halign="center">
                Common Terms Used in the
                Texas Juvenile Justice System
        	</std-title>
            <br/>
            
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Adjudication Hearing</b> - A hearing where the judge or jury determines 
                whether your child committed the alleged offense or is innocent of the charge.            
        	</std-paragraph>
            <br/>
        
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Defense Attorney</b> - A lawyer who represents your child and makes 
                sure that your child&apos;s rights are protected.  The juvenile court must appoint an attorney to 
                represent your child if the court finds that you cannot afford to hire an attorney.
        	</std-paragraph>
            <br/>
        
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Discretionary Transfer Hearing</b> - A hearing where the judge decides 
                whether to transfer your child&apos;s case to a criminal court where your child will be prosecuted 
                as an adult.            
        	</std-paragraph>
            <br/>
        
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Disposition Hearing</b> - A separate hearing that occurs after the 
                adjudication hearing when the final decision or result of your child&apos;s case is made by the 
                judge or jury and where your child may be placed on probation or committed to the Texas 
                Juvenile Justice Department.            
        	</std-paragraph>
            <br/>
        
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Modification Hearing</b> - A hearing to change the previous conditions 
                of your child&apos;s probation or to revoke his probation when your child is accused of violating 
                the conditions of probation.              
        	</std-paragraph>
            <br/>
        
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Petition/Motion</b> - A written legal document filed by the prosecutor 
                that informs you and your child of the offense your child is alleged to have committed and 
                provides the date, time and place of any future court dates.  You and your child must be given 
                a copy of this document.            
        	</std-paragraph>
            <br/>
            
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Prosecutor</b> - Lawyers who work for county, district or criminal district 
                attorneys&apos; offices who handle juvenile cases.  The persons are usually referred to as District 
                Attorney, D.A., Assistant District Attorney, County Attorney or Assistant County Attorney.             
        	</std-paragraph>
            <br/>
            
            <std-paragraph>
                <b>Texas Juvenile Justice Department</b> - A state agency that operates secure correctional 
                facilities for juveniles committed there by the juvenile court.            
        	</std-paragraph>
            
        </cell>
	</table>

    
    <!--  =============================================================================================================
        Page 3  
    -->
    
	<new-page size="LETTER" margin-left="20" margin-right="20" margin-top="20" margin-bottom="20">
	</new-page>

    <std-title>
        PLEASE COMPLETE AND RETURN THIS FORM TO THE JUVENILE PROBATION DEPARTMENT ON OR BEFORE  ${courtDate}.
    </std-title>
    
    <std-title halign="center">
        CAUSE NO. ${petitionNumber}
    </std-title>

	<table columns="3" border-style="none" border-width="0" widths="8,1,8" padding="2">
        <table-row>
            <cell halign="left" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-title>
                    IN THE INTEREST OF: <br/>
                    <br/>
                    ${juvenileName}<br/>
                    <br/>
                    A JUVENILE<br/>
            	</std-title>
            </cell>
            <cell halign="left" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-title>
                    .<br/>
                    .<br/>
                    .<br/>
                    .<br/>
                    .<br/>
                </std-title>
            </cell>
            <cell halign="left" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-title>
                    IN THE ${courtName} DISTRICT COURT<br/>
                    HARRIS COUNTY, TEXAS
            	</std-title>
            </cell>
        </table-row>
	</table>
	<br/>

    <std-title halign="center">
        PARENTAL WRITTEN STATEMENT 
    </std-title>
	<br/>

    <std-paragraph>
        I, ________________________________________________________________________, a parent or other person responsible 
        for the above named juvenile, submit this written statement as authorized under Texas Family Code Section 61.104.  
        I would like to provide the following information so that the court can have my input for a better understanding 
        of the needs and strengths of my child, our family and any other information important to the disposition of this case:
    </std-paragraph>
    <br/>
    
    <std-paragraph>
        1.	<b>Background.</b>  The court should know the following information about my child&apos;s background.  (Use this space to 
        describe information such as important events, drug problems or hardships that you believe have contributed to the 
        circumstances your child is currently facing.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>

    <std-paragraph>
        2.	<b>Medical and Psychological.</b>  The court should know the following medical and psychological history about my child.  
        (Use this space to describe any medical conditions, illnesses, physical disabilities, medication needs, psychological 
        history, psychological treatment or counseling, suicidal history, etc.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>

    <!--  =============================================================================================================
        Page 4 
    -->
    
	<new-page size="LETTER" margin-left="20" margin-right="20" margin-top="20" margin-bottom="20">
	</new-page>
    
    <std-paragraph>
        3.	<b>Education.</b>   The court should know the following information about my child&apos;s school history. (Use this space 
        to describe information such as any achievements or problems your child may have experienced in school including 
        attendance, grades, special education, disciplinary problems, conflicts, extra-curricular activities, awards, 
        sports, special skills and work, etc.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>

    <std-paragraph>
        4.	<b>Home Environment.</b>  My child&apos;s home environment and family situation can best be described as: (Use this space 
        to tell the court about your child&apos;s home life and environment such as information about how your child gets along 
        with you, his or her brothers and sisters or any other person living at home, your child&apos;s willingness to perform 
        chores and other work around the house, behavior and discipline issues, whether your child has a job that adds to 
        the household income, positive or negative neighborhood influences, etc.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>
    
    <std-paragraph>
        5.	<b>Supervision.</b>  If the court places my child under my supervision, I plan to help my child stay out of trouble 
        while on probation by:  (Use this space to tell the court information such as your ability to supervise your child, 
        any additional supportive adults who are available to assist you, problems you may have providing supervision, your 
        plan to assist the probation department in making sure that your child will attend school and do everything the 
        probation office requires, etc.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>
    
    <!--  =============================================================================================================
        Page 5 
    -->
    
	<new-page size="LETTER" margin-left="20" margin-right="20" margin-top="20" margin-bottom="20">
	</new-page>
    
    <std-paragraph>
        6.	<b>Child&apos;s Positive Traits.</b>  The court should know the following good things about my child. (Use this space to tell 
        the judge information such as any special achievements, character traits, volunteer work, past jobs, clubs, organizations, 
        community or church activities in which your child participates.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>
    
    <std-paragraph>
        7.	<b>Recommended Outcome.</b>  When the court considers the final outcome of my child&apos;s case, I recommend that the judge order 
        the following:  (Use this space to tell the judge what you think should happen to your child in this case.  What you feel 
        your child&apos;s needs are.  You may also want to discuss what will happen to your family if your child is removed from your 
        custody and placed outside your home.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>
    
    <std-paragraph>
        8.	<b>Additional Information.</b> The court should know the following important information that would be helpful to the court 
        in making a final decision.  (Use this space to provide the judge with any information that you feel may influence the 
        judge when making a final decision.)<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
        <br/>
        ___________________________________________________________________________________________________<br/>
    </std-paragraph>

    <std-paragraph>
        All the information I have provided to the court in this Parental Written Statement is true and correct to the best of 
        my knowledge and belief.
    </std-paragraph>
    <br/>
    
	<table columns="2" border-style="none" border-width="0" widths="1,1" padding="0">
        <table-row>
            <cell halign="left" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-paragraph>
                    ___________________________________________ <br/>
                    Signature of Parent or Other Person<br/>
                    <br/>
                    ___________________________________________<br/>
                    Printed Name of Parent or Other Person
            	</std-paragraph>
            </cell>
            <cell halign="right" valign="top" leading="1" padding-top="0" line-spacing="1">
            	<std-paragraph>
                    Date Signed: ______________________________
            	</std-paragraph>
            </cell>
        </table-row>
	</table>

    
</document>
